# Ebuka Odini

ebukaodini@gmail.com / +2349093590559 / 39, Aliu Bisiriyu Street, Lagos, Lagos

#### **Summary**

Software Engineer with +6 years of professional experience building web and mobile applications with Node, React, PHP and Flutter.

Blending the art of design and logic with skill of programming to deliver engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization and also follows best practices to improve product quality.

Loves team work and collaboration.

#### Experience

## **Fullstack Javascript Engineer**

Tensei • Lagos, Lagos 10/2021 - 03/2022

#### Responsibilities:

- Developed new user-facing features
- Developed backend feature architectures
- Built reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/Ux designs
- · Optimized application for maximum speed and scalability
- Implemented security best practices in developing backend and frontend features
- Occasionally Pair programmed wth other team members
- Collaborated with other team members and stakeholders
- Improved components of the Framework by 93 on a rating scale of 100 points, resulting in a 40% increase in enduser productivity
- Developed new components of the Framework that improved the effectiveness of the application, resulting in a 23% increare in end-user productivity

# **Software Engineer (Contract)**

Spicy Guitar Academy • Lagos, Lagos

02/2021 - 10/2021

- Designed the website update on Figma.
- Developed the updated website.
- Integrated mutilple payment services into the mobile application
- Built the web version of the mobile application

# Software Engineer (Contract)

Sports Fans Club • Lagos, Lagos

11/2019 - 03/2021

- Developed the frontend application for both customers and administrators.
- Developed the backend API for integrating with the frontend.
- Integrated payment and other third party APIs into the application.

# Software Engineer

Mira Technologies Ltd. • Lagos, Lagos

11/2019 - 03/2021

- Sysbanker EE
  - Developed the backend APIs of the application.

- Developed some frontend features in the application.
- Deployed and maintained the application.
- Integrated the application with other third party APIs.
- · Mira Bulk Mail
  - Developed the frontend application.
  - Developed the backend APIs for integrating with the frontend.
  - Deployed and mainitained the application.

## **Software Engineer (Contract)**

Spicy Guitar Academy • Lagos, Lagos 02/2019 - 12/2019

- Developed the mobile application.
- Developed the administrator portal.
- Developed the backend APIs for integrating with the mobile application and the administrator portal.

## **Software Engineer**

Mira Technologies Ltd. • Lagos, Lagos

07/2018 - 03/2019

- HaboPay
  - Developed the backend APIs for the payment platform.
- · Habo Global Sanitary Wears
  - Developed the e-commerce backend API for the mobile application.
  - Developed the administrator portal to manage products, orders, payments and customer accounts.
- · Victory Gold Networks
  - Developed the website.
  - Developed the admin portal of the application.
  - Deployed and maintained the application.

# Software Developer

Freelancer • Benin, Edo State

05/2017 - 08/2019

- Fully Fuzzy Linear Programming Problem Software
  - Developed the desktop application.
- Myscriptz
  - Developed the frontend application.
  - Developed the backend APIs to integrate with the frontend application.
  - Deployed the application.
- Automated Loan Management System
  - Developed the desktop application.

#### **Skills**

Javascript, Typescript, Dart, PHP, React, Flutter, Node.js, Next.js, Redux, HTML, CSS, SCSS (Sassy Cascading Style Sheets), Bootstrap, Jquery, Mysql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RxDB, REST, GraphQL, Git, Docker, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Mocha, Jest, Chai

#### **Education**

### **Computer Science**

University of Benin • Benin, Edo State 12/2019

Graduated with Second Class (Upper) honor.

#### **Publications**

1. An Approach Towards the Development of Init Framework

Journal of Electrical Engineering, Electronics, Control and Computer Science. *Published* 2022 <u>View Publication</u>

#### **Certifications & Awards**

Winner, University of Benin App Contest 2019, Cybrary Secure Coding Certificate

# Languages

English, Yoruba, Igbo

#### Links

- LinkedIn
- Github
- <u>Twitter</u>
- Portfolio
- Dev Blog